Christian Angeles

LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

Location: Hidalgo, Mexico Email: chris_uriel09@hotmail.com| Mobile: +52 7712404119

FULL STACK DEVELOPER + JR. DATA SCIENTIST

Software Engineer with over **2 years of experience** developing projects using **Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript**. I have knowledge of popular frameworks such as **Angular and FastAPI** I also have comprehensive training, as well as hands-on experience in applied machine learning projects.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages : Python, JavaScript, R, HTML, C#

Frameworks : Angular, FastAPI

ML Libraries : Tensorflow, Pytorch, Keras

Databases : SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Dev Tools : Visual Studio Code, Git, Jupyter Notebooks, Tableau

EXPERIENCE

Klover.ai

Machine Learning Engineer Intern

Jun 2023 - Oct 2023

Remote – Ruston, United States

- Reading and discussing recent articles and papers in the field of **Machine Leaarning** and **Artificial Intelligence**. In some cases, attempts were also made to replicate the experiments and findings of the authors.
- Cleaning and preparing datasets for model training and evaluation.
- Implementing and experimenting with different machine learning algorithms and architectures, using tools like
 TensorFlow and PyTorch to enhance the efficiency and scalability of the models.
- Measuring **accuracy**, **recall**, **F1-score**, and other relevant metrics, and conducting **A/B tests** to compare the performance of different models or approaches.

Fullstack Developer

Information Insight

Jan 2021 – Sep 2023 Remote – Mexico City, Mexico

- Management of +80 different databases using SQL Server
- Worked with AWS Lambda to develop serverless microservices using Python or C#
- Application of **Angular** to optimize **several internal applications**, managing to improve the performance of other departments.
- Develop endpoints for multiple APIs through **FastAPI** simplifying code and saving computational cost, all to optimize various processes.

Data Analyst

Jun 2020 – Dec 2020 Pachuca, Mexico

Binahria Analytics

- Development of electoral data visualization system, for political analysis. Applying Angular, Flask, QGis.
- Implementation and development of object detection models with **Tensorflow**, applied to a **system of surveillance for detection of license plates** with an accuracy of 91%.
- Planning and development of predictive systems applied to the **forecast of renewable energies requirements** for self-sustaining housing complexes.

EDUCATION

Universidad Politécnica de Pachuca

Software Engineering

Hidalgo, Mexico Sep 2016 – Feb 2020

PROJECTS

Diabetic retinopathy detector

Python, Tensorflow, Neural Networks, Git

Source Code

- Development and implementation of a **Convolutional neural network** applied to images, seeking to diagnose diabetic retinopathy from ocular fundus.
- Working with Messidor and APTOS datasets to achieve 80% diagnostic accuracy

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Third place "Aerospace Challenge" on Cyber IA Hackathon 2021
- <u>Second place</u> "IoT/Smart Cities" on Campus Party Hackathon 2017 (CPMX8)
- Special guest "Taller conjunto sobre Deep Learning y Ciencia de Datos" in CIMAT Guanajuato, México 2019.
- <u>Special guest</u> "**Séptimo Seminario y Sexta Escuela Nacional de Aprendizaje e Inteligencia Computacional"** in BUAP Puebla, México 2019.

LANGUAGES

- Spanish(Native)
- English(B2)